

Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Java, JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, HTML, CSS/SCSS, SQL

LIBRARIES & FRAMEWORKS

Spring boot, Angular, React, Vue, Node.js, Express

TOOLS & PLATFORMS

IntelliJ, Git, Webpack, VS code, Jenkins

JOSEPH DIAS

PROFILE

An expert software developer with 8+ years of experience in designing and creating scalable software, writing clean and functional code for both front-end and back-end. Able to minimize system downtime and quickly respond to changing business needs. A seasoned full-stack developer with experience in training other developers, providing active feedback and participating in the hiring process.

CONTACT

PHONE:

+44 7495275404

Emai

josephdias92@gmail.com

Github Links:

josephdias92 (Joseph Dias) · GitHub

Profile Links: Joseph Dias

Work Experience

FULL STACK ENGINEER
CREDIT SUISSE, LONDON (AVP)
Oct 2019 – Present

Currently working on IICAPS EMEA project for SOX application at Credit Suisse in London

Promoted to Assistant Vice President (AVP) in London from ENO 3

Successfully migrated 5 applications from JAP to Angular and Spring Boot using Agile Methodology Acting as IT Owner for Asset Servicing Portal and Seclib applications

Guided and coached new team members in Pune and Zurich on various technologies related to Asset Servicing applications

Implemented CI/CD for Asset Servicing Portal Proposed and implementing micro frontend architecture

Built reusable libraries (SECLIB) and published to InnerSource for wider groups within Credit Suisse India

Delivered high-quality software for SRD II program to support business in meeting key regulatory requirements Provided swift resolutions to production stability issues for the business

Made major contributions to hiring for Operations Technology India, including conducting interviews and making hiring decisions.

LEAD PROJECT ENGINEER
PERSISTENT SYSTEM LIMITED, GOA
July 2017 - Oct 2019

Promoted to Lead Project Engineer from Senior Front-End Developer

Responsible for end-to-end project delivery, including working on a project to migrate an AppDynamics application from Adobe Flash to Angular and Spring Boot technology

Handled clients such as IBM in research projects for three different applications, including building the application architecture

JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER
SRIJAN TECHNOLOGIES, GOA
Feb 2016 - June 2017

Worked with international clients to understand business needs and develop software solutions with necessary validations.

Developed software to analyze and process data and statistics, which works both online and offline.

Promoted technology awareness through code sprints, sessions, demos, blogs, and presentations.

Took complete ownership of code quality, including reviewing, guiding, and supporting other developers as needed.

Actively participated in tech discussions, estimations, and supported Tech Leads in technical/architectural decisions.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER
GARUD TECHNOLOGIES, GOA
July 2015 - Jan 2016

Created Angular project architecture. Created WebAPI in C# MVC. Deployed Angular application. Worked with Ionic framework (hybrid Application)

Internship
Open Destination Private Limited
Jan 2015 - June 2015

EDUCATION

MASTER OF COMPUTER APPLICATION GOA UNIVERSITY

May 2012 - June 2015

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER APPLICATION ROSARY COLLEGE, NAVELIM, GOA July 2009 - April 2012